Willian Silva

English | French

P Longueuil (Québec)

514 772 - 2504

⊠ williandes.silva@yahoo.ca

www.linkedin.com/in/silvawill https://williangust.github.io/page-willian/



OBJECTIVE

With a bachelor's degree in engineering and an AEC in programming, I have over 15 years of industry experience, including 2 years in programming. My personal and professional journey has enhanced my programming skills and solidified my professional approach. I am determined to leverage my experience and passion for programming by joining a creative team as a developer and create unparalleled value in this field.



TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Language

JavaScript ES5/ES6	****
jQuery	****
CSS 3	****
HTML	****
Node.js	****
Ruby	****
PHP	***
C#	****

Framework

ASP.NET	** **
Bootstrap	***
Express.js	** ***
Ruby on Rails	***
Entity Framework	** ***
.NET	** ***

Data Base

SQL	***
MySQL	***
NoSQL (MongoDB)	** **



SKILLS

- ✓ Creativity, team spirit, efficiency, and organizational skills
- ✓ Ease of adaptation, great curiosity and interest in research and novelty
- ✓ Programming new feature
- ✓ Bug fixes
- ✓ Implementation of customer requirements
- ✓ Familiar with Linux and Windows environments
- ✓ Knowledge of Photoshop and Illustrator



EDUCATION

2021 (obtention Déc.)

AEC in Transactional Web Development

Collège Ahuntsic (www.collegeahuntsic.qc.ca)

2020

Bootcamp - Web Development

Lighthouse Labs Inc - Canada (www.lighthouselabs.ca)

B.S. in Chemical Engineering*

Université Oswaldo Cruz (www.oswaldocruz.br)

* Équivalence délivrée par le Ministère du Québec (MIDI) en 2010



EXPERIENCE

Dec.2021 - Mar.2023

Programmer Analyst, Jr - M2i3 Inc.

www.m2i3.com

- Design and maintain MySQL databases
- Design the frontend of the application using RoR, Silverstripe, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and jQuery
- Design the backend of the application using Active Records and SQL queries
- Develop the user interface
- Experience with Docker Compose
- Analyze and program in PHP (WordPress and Silverstripe)
- Participate in the development of Restful APIs
- Conduct unit testing and validation testing with Capybara and minitest



A OTHER EXPERIENCES

2018 - 2021

R&D Chemist – Industries Pepin Ltd – Montreal

Company specialized in the manufacturing and distribution of industrial paint

2016 - 2018

R&D Chemist – Evotech Ind – Longueuil

Company specialized in industrial paint. A world-class supplier in the field of doors and windows, utility vehicles, and others

2011 - 2013

R&D Chemist – Protech Chemical – Montreal

A leading company in the field of formulation and manufacturing of powder coatings

2010 - 2011

R&D Chemistry Technician – Sogel Inc – Longueuil

Company specialized in the formulation and manufacturing of high-performance gelcoats for the composite materials industry



VOLUNTEERING | SOCIAL INVOLVEMENT

2023

Volunteer coach - CSL - Longueuil

Club Soccer Longueuil